FURKAN OZDEMIR

Fairfax, VA 20120 ♦ ozdemirfrank@gmail.com ♦ (646) 875-7950 ♦ Linkedin.com/in/frknozdmr ♦ http://furkanozdemir.info

PROFILE

Certified Cybersecurity professional with three years of experience working with the IT team. Skilled in incident response, vulnerability scanning, network defense, cloud security, reverse engineering, risk management and malware analysis.

Technical Skills: C++, C#, Python, Bash, Java, SQL, JavaScript, CSS/HTML, Unix Shell, OS X, Windows, and Linux

Technical Tools: Odoo, GIT, QRadar SIEM, Splunk

EDUCATION

City University of New York, Brooklyn College

BS in Computer & Information Science

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

REACH CONCEPT

Chantilly, VA

Jan 2020 – Oct 2022

Information Security Engineer

- Worked with the development teams for security-focused design and secure coding.
- Performed risk assessments to identify system vulnerabilities and create Risk Assessment Reports for the client companies.
- Identified incidents and provided incident response support to client companies.
- Analyzed and reported TCP/IP network traffic and event logs to secure companies' cloud-based ERP software data.
- Installed and updated antivirus software to over 2,000 company devices and set up checkpoint firewalls to secure the network.
- Controlled user access management and trained staff on security vulnerabilities.

REACH CONCEPT Chantilly, VA

IT Specialist

Jan 2019 – Jan 2020

- Developed a customized ERP software system for over twenty clients that gathers their sales/reporting, scheduling, and day to day operations under one unified cloud-based system, including accounting, sales, purchase, manufacturing, inventory management and CRM using C++.
- Managed and helped the developer team to develop e-commerce websites and mobile apps for clients including dealer login system using Python, JavaScript, and CSS.
- Assigned and oversaw the daily tasks of a team of five developers to maintain quality of the service provided to clients by establishing and enforcing organizational standards and implement security measures.

ALZERINA New York, NY

Software / Web Developer Intern

Sep 2018 - Jan 2019

- Helped developing as well as maintaining company's website while correcting errors using C++, HTML, Java Script, CSS.
- Assisted in web page and asset auditing, database management, reports generation, etc.
- Integrated new clients into database and ensured information kept up to date for over one-thousand clients using SQL.
- Provided assistance in creating and presenting stories, images, and videos in company's web content management system.
- Worked with the marketing department twice per week to gather highly popular content for the company's website.

NYC ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT CORPORATION

New York, NY

Community Technology Team member

Jan 2017 – Jan 2018

- Undertook assigned projects involving implementation of creating public Wi-Fi mesh networks for New York City residents.
- Performed periodic preventive maintenance and calibration procedures for public Wi-Fi control systems twice per week.
- Assisted in continuously reviewing strategies to maximize Wi-Fi efficiency, and reliability.
- Troubleshoot problems as they may arise in Wi-Fi distribution mechanism to prevent signal losses in extreme weather conditions, or natural disasters.

CERTIFICATIONS

IBM Cybersecurity Analyst Professional Certificate.

- Developed knowledge of cybersecurity analyst tools including data protection; endpoint protection, SIEM, and system and network fundamentals.
- Acquired knowledge around key compliance and thread intelligence important in today's cybersecurity landscape.
- Gained skills for incident responses and forensics.

Technical Project Management Certificate by Bob McGannon.